I want to talk about managing media
on your website.
On the old site,
adding media to your content
was a two step process.
We needed to add it to our media library.
Copy the URL.
Go to our content and embed the media.
Now it's no longer a two step process
and we don't really need to manage
our media here.
This is the dashboard.
Media block.
We can look at our media here.
We can edit it.
We can if we scroll
all the way down to the bottom
see more, we can search.
For media.
But ultimately what we want to do
is add it to a
piece of content.
So let's say we have a news message.
And we want to add an image to it.
Now something to think
about
when you're adding images to your website
is that the images need to have
alternative text for people with vision
impairments or other impairments
that don't allow them to view the image.
We don't want to leave them out.
We don't want our, you know,
we want our content to reach everybody.
And there's also our legal obligation
to make sure that our content
is accessible
to those people with disabilities.
So let's use an example here.
Let's say we wanted to upload this
wild cat picture.
Now one issue with this picture
is that it actually contains text
within the picture.
So we need to make sure that all of that
text is in our alternative text.
We can insert that image.
And we're just
going to use this as a test.
And there's our image.
And if you look at the source code
you can see that
when somebody comes through the screen
reader it's going to read this alt
text.
So let's delete that.
And take a look at another
image.
Let's say we wanted to post this image
about the book fair.
Now as you can see, this
image contains a lot of text.
In order to make this accessible.
We would need to take all of this text
and put it in the alternative text field.
That doesn't seem like
it's really a good idea.
Because think of the experience where
somebody actually using a screen reader
for them to have it
go through all of this text
completely without any structure.
It's going to be very difficult
for them to understand.
Instead, what you should do
is anytime
you have an image with text in it,
you need to put the text that's
in the image, actually in the news post.
Now, what you would do
is go back
to the person who created the image
and ask them for a
text document,
a word document, you know, whatever
kind of design documents
they're using to create that image.
And normally it will have the text in it,
you know, as the text needs to be
kind of agreed upon before
the image is created.
Now, failing that, now,
there may be some tools that can help
you extract the text from this image.
This is an image.
This isn't really text,
but if I open this on my Mac with preview,
it has the ability to try to.
Parse all that text so I can copy it.
I'm going a copy of that text,
and I don't have any idea
whether this has formatting or anything,
so I'm going to play it safe. And.
Paste it in the text.
Add it.
I'm going to say.
Do I have to go through and reformat
all of this?
Instead of having that
there, I'm going to make this the title.
I don't like how it's all caps. So.
We don't need to tell them what school
it is.
They know it looks like this is an event.
So honestly,
this should probably be an event.
Instead of being a news item,
but that's okay.
Maybe we can
add some headers
to make this a little more
clear. What's happening?
Okay, so this is a bulleted list.
I need to refer to the picture to see.
This is kind of referring to these lists.
So let's go ahead.
Make this another header.
Really?
This should not be all caps.
We have a link here.
Hashtag.
You know what?
I don't know what that's for.
And there we go.
So let's just say.
Let's
use that for some way.
And now we have a news post
that anybody can read.
Regardless of whether they have
a vision impairment or not.
Now let's take a look at a document.
You know that.
Let's say I want to add a new document.
And it's a flier about spring jazz
concert.
Well.
We look at this,
we see that we have once again, a
similar to how an image should not have
text.
Documents should be avoided.
Almost always.
There are ways to make PDFs accessible,
but it's a lot of work
and it takes specialized knowledge.
So again, just like the image,
what we should do instead
you can see it's hard.
It's hard even to select this text.
So imagine if you were using a screen
reader.
The screen reads Spring concert.
And then it doesn't know
where to go to next.
You can see
it wants to go down to Mount Hebron.
So we're going to have to.
Sort of put this in any tab.
Okay.
And I can't even select this text
properly.
Now, once again,
I have a news message
that can be read by everybody.
We're not leaving out people
with vision impairments.
So I just want to emphasize that while
I've done my best to make.
Managing media easier after the upgrade,
media really should be used sparingly
because in order
to make it accessible for everybody,
it takes a lot of work.
So the best thing to do is
take anything
out of a body, of any document or image
and paste it into the body
of your news item
or event or anything else.
While I was editing this video,
I realized that I should show you a way
that you can spruce up this,
news post with an image
while maintaining accessibility.
So we have all of the copy
that we want in here,
but we would like a decorative image
to kind of give people,
you know, it's not as exciting
as, you know,
this nice, well-designed flier.
And, well, we can't include the flier.
What we can do.
Is make an image of the flier
that that removes all of the text.
You may not have illustrator.
But whoever created the image for
you should be able to extract something
that is decorative for the page.
So now I've created an image
from the flier
that's just decorative. And.
Now, this is an image
that I could actually write
some good old text for.
Now we have our image in our news post.